Upton Sinclair Miscellaneous Materials VII: Articles about Sinclair and His Works, 1906-1965 PS3537.I85 (InU-Li-VAE1864)
Lilly Library
- Sinclair notified he is 'Republican' nominee [for governor] (In Los Angeles record. Sept. 24, 1930), PS3537.I85 Z8346 (Box No Box)
- Sinclair out as candidate, Epic goes on. (In The Pasadena post. Feb. 13, 1936. p. 1: port.), PS3537.I85 Z8347 (Box No Box)
- Sinclair requests hearing. (The capital times. Madison, Wisc. May 2, [1922] p. [1]) Sinclair demands a hearing on the issue raised by being denied the use of the university building., PS3537.I85 Z83472 (Box No Box)
- Sinclair told to quit?: Farley agent said to be on way here to induce him to withdraw in favor of Haight. (In The Hollywood reporter. v. 23, no. 47, Oct. 30, 1934. p. [1]–2.), PS3537.I85 Z83474 (Box No Box)
- Sinclair's Boston. (In The equitist. Phoenix, Ariz. no. 579–581, Oct. 11–25, 1929. p. 3–4, 4, 3–4), PS3537.I85 Z84 (Box No Box)
- Sinclair prototype of Lasalle. (In Pacific weekly. Carmel, Calif. v. 4, no. 9, Mar. 2, 1936. p. 112] A letter to the editor signed: H.K., PS3537.I85 Z8414 (Box No Box)
- Sinclair's son leads anti–war faction: is outgrowth of social science society considered 'too conservative.' (From The Milwaukee news. Apr. 9, 1924), PS3537.I85 Z842 (Box No Box)
- Smertenko, Johan Jacob, 1895– Chronicle of the twentienth century: Wide is the gate, by Upton Sinclair. (From Underground reporter. [1943] p. 84) Book review., PS3537.I85 Z8423 (Box No Box)
- The soapbox art, especially that practiced by Upton Sinclair which has brought down the wrath of the reviewer through "Mammonart." (From The New York telegraph. July 12, 1925. ill.), PS3537.I85 Z8424 (Box No Box)
- The Jimmie Higgins contest: a competition to discover who is the best worker for Socialism — the best Jimmie Higgins — in the United States will be held by the Socialist Party of America from Sept. 1, 1930 to March 1, 1931. Chicago: Socialist Party of America, [1930] 1 leaf; 23 x 41 cm. Poster announcing the contest and posting the awards, which range all the way from a trip to "Red Vienna" to various Socialist books., PS3537.I85 Z8425 (Box No Box)
- State Democratic call presages EPIC fight: Olson's meet to precede Sinclair's. (In Illustrated daily news. Los Angeles. Jan. 14, 1936. p. 3), PS3537.I85 Z84256 (Box No Box)
- Steffens, Lincoln, 1866–1936. Upton Sinclair's God. (In Pacific weekly. Feb. 17, 1936. p. 84) Review of Sinclair's What God means to me., PS3537.I85 Z84258 (Box No Box)
- Stewart, Kenneth Norman. Upton Sinclair and his EPIC plan for California: crusading author, read out of the Socialist Party as "opportunistic" is making a determined fight for the Democratic nomination for governor — and he may win it / by Kenneth Stewart. (In The literary digest. v. 118, no. 8, Aug. 25, 1934. p. 10: port.), PS3537.I85 Z84259 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Fuller, Meta. [Letter to the editor] (In Time magazine. Mar. 29, 1954. p. 10) Letter from the first wife of Upton Sinclair in which she takes exception to a letter Sinclair wrote to Time on March 8., PS3537.I85 Z8426 (Box No Box)
- A "study" of journalism. (From The San Francisco call–post. Feb. 25, 1920) Criticism of Sinclair's thesis in "The brass check"; ms. comments by Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z8427 (Box No Box)
- Swados, Harvey. The world of Upton Sinclair / by Harvey Swados. (In The Alantic. v. 208, no. 6, Dec. 1961. p. 96–102), PS3537.I85 Z84274 (Box No Box)
- Swaffer, Hannen. I've met them all: Upton Sinclair, his books have opened the minds of millions of people: Norman Lindsay, he has fought all his life. (In Weekly illustrated. Feb. 2, 1935. p. 13, 19: ports.), PS3537.I85 Z84276 (Box No Box)
- Symes, Lillian, b. 1895. After EPIC in California / by Lillian Symes. (In The nation. Apr. 22, 1936. p. 509–511), PS3537.I85 Z8428 (Box No Box)
- A teetotaler. (In The imperial magazine. Oct. 1956. p. 15–16) Comment on Sinclair's "The cup of fury.", PS3537.I85 Z84284 (Box No Box)
- Telepathy. (In Time magazine. v. 19, no. 9, Feb. 29, 1932. p. 44) News item in the Science section referring to Sinclair's Mental radio., PS3537.I85 Z84287 (Box No Box)
- O. Henry in prison: Theatre Mart. (From Rob Wagner's script. Beverly Hills, Calif. Jan. 17, 1931. p. 12–13) Review of the play., PS3537.I85 Z8432 (Box No Box)
- This EPIC situation. (In Pacific weekly. v. 2, no. 24, June 14, 1935. p. 1) An editorial., PS3537.I85 Z8433 (Box No Box)
- This month's birthday. (In Foy libra: Foyles Bookshop magazine. no. 219, Sept. 1945. p. iv) Birthday greetings to Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z84333 (Box No Box)
- Thomson, Morgan. The Chicago "Jungle" re–visited: a quiet talk with Upton Sinclair, America's great Socialist writer: Morgan Thomson's American notebook. (In Forward. v. 46, no. 7, Feb. 16, 1952. p. 5–6), PS3537.I85 Z84336 (Box No Box)
- Thomson, Morgan. The greatest racket of them all: a review by Morgan Thomson of Upton Sinclair's newest "World's end" novel. (In Forward. v. 41, no. 43, Nov. 8, 1947. p. 2: port.) Review of "A world to win.", PS3537.I85 Z84337 (Box No Box)
- Those misleading headlines. (From The New York press. May 6, 1914) A joke about Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z8434 (Box No Box)
- Through a glass darkly. (In Time. Apr. 30, 1956. p. 116, 118) Review of "The cup of fury.", PS3537.I85 Z8436 2 copies (Box No Box)
- To enforce the Sabbath law: Upton Sinclair, Ardenite, says he will inaugurate a crusade. (Clipping from unidentified newspaper. Aug. 1911), PS3537.I85 Z844 (Box No Box)
- The torch of the Upton Sinclair YCC. v. 1, no. 2, Dec. 1, 1932. New York. 7 p. Mimeographed copy of the magazine of the Upton Sinclair Young Circle Club., PS3537.I85 Z8442 (Box No Box)
- A trap for the feet of genius: drink and men of letters: Upton Sinclair's experiences. (In The tribune. Capetown, South Africa. Sept. 1933. p. 109–111) A review of Sinclair's "Money writes!" and "Candid reminiscences.", PS3537.I85 Z844235 (Box No Box)
- A trustful brain truster. (From Rob Wagner's "Script." Beverly Hills, Calif. Mar. 17, 1934. 1 p.) An offprint., PS3537.I85 Z84424 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Twenty–five years ago today: March 4, 1906. (From editorial page of San Francisco Chronicle. Mar. 4, 1931) Referring to The jungle, by U. Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z84426 (Box No Box)
- Two letters concerning the novelette, "What Didymus did." 1 p. Mimeographed. The letters are by Albert Einstein and C.G. Jung., PS3537.I85 Z84427 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Two noted members of the Arden colony with types of dwellings erected there. (In The evening telegraph. Philadelphia. Aug. 2, 1911. p. 1: ill., ports.) Brief article concerning Upton Sinclair and George Brown, together pictures of the men and their homes in Arden., PS3537.I85 Z84428 (Box No Box)
- The undersigned Californians endorse the announced candidacy of Upton Sinclair for the governorship of our state. [S.l.: s.n., 1926] 1 leaf; 22 x 28 cm. Signers: A. Bruce Anthony, Herman Lissauer, Mark Lee Luther, Rob Wagner, Lewis Browne, Myna Browne, Jim Tully., PS3537.I85 Z8443 2 copies (Box No Box)
- The undersigned holders, or former holders of academic positions join in recommending to the Swedish Academy the name of Upton Sinclair as candidate for the award of the Nobel Prize for literature. [S.l.: s.n., 1931] 1 leaf; 22 x 28 cm. List of signers headed by Harry Elmer Barnes., PS3537.I85 Z8445 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Uppy Sinclair sings in verse of jail and he is not so worse: writes, with hammer in his hand, of Arden and its martyr band. (From The North American. Philadelphia. no. 318, Aug. 3, 1911. p. 1, 6: ports.), PS3537.I85 Z845 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. New York, 1927. (From The New York Times. Sept. 4, 1927) An unsigned review of Floyd Dell's "Upton Sinclair.", PS3537.I85 Z8455 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. (From The new masses. Dec. 22, 1942. p. 16) An editorial., PS3537.I85 Z8456 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. (Clipping from an unidentified newspaper. May 10, 1961) Commenting upon Sinclair's issuing a memorial edition of "Southern Belle.", PS3537.I85 Z846 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. (From Writer's digest. Mar. 1930. p. 21) An informal interview with Upton Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z847 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. Indianapolis, 1927. (From The Indianapolis news. Aug. 20, 1927) Review of Floyd Dell's Biography of Upton Sincliar., PS3537.I85 Z848 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. (In T.P.'s and Cassell's weekly. v. 8, no. 203 (new series), Sept. 17, 1927. p. [1]) Photograph of Sinclair, with brief caption relating of the banning of his novel Oil! in Boston., PS3537.I85 Z849 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair and the Los Angeles Times. (From Seattle Union Record. Editorial section. Jan. 8, 1920. p. [10]) An editorial., PS3537.I85 Z85 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair. (In The liberator. v. 1, no. 10, Dec. 1918. p. 7–8) An uncomplimentary comment on Sinclair as a Socialist., PS3537.I85 Z86 (Box No Box)
- [Upton Sinclair and the publishers] (In Swit. Lemberg, East Galicia. Nov. 1, 1925. p. 10–11: port.) Title translated from the Ukrainian., PS3537.I85 Z863 (Box No Box)
- Upton asks leave to print. (In Public relations. Oct. 1925. p. 22–25) Includes letter from Sinclair about the evil effects of Big business on politics; this article is in answer to Sinclair's letter., PS3537.I85 Z867 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair at 80. (In The new republic. v. 139, no. 13, Sept. 29, 1958. p. 6) An editorial., PS3537.I85 Z8672 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair at San Pedro. (In So this is liberty! New York: American Civil Liberties Union. June, 1924. p. 7–9) Includes Sinclair's account of his arrest in connection with his protest against the treatment of 600 striking longshoremen in Los Angeles., PS3537.I85 Z8674 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair, author of "The jungle." (In The journalist. New York. v. 38, no. 23, Mar. 24, 1906. p. [1]) Large portrait of Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z868 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair, "Co–op." (In Abstinenter Sozialist. Zürich. v. 32, no. 9, Sept. 1937. p. [3]) A brief review of Co–op., PS3537.I85 Z872 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair, EPIC candidate. (In Vanity fair. Sept. 1934) Large portrait of Sinclair with a brief comment on his candidacy for governor of California., PS3537.I85 Z874 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair, et. al. refused to pay a fine imposed for breaking the Sunday laws and were given eighteen hours each in the workhouse — they will be released to–day. (From The news. Wilmington, Del. Aug. 2, 1911), PS3537.I85 Z88 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair favoriet voor post van gouverneur van Californië. (In Vrede: organ van het vredes studie bureau. v. 7, no. 10, Oct. 1934. p. 138–140), PS3537.I85 Z885 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair gives approval for 'Lanny Budd' TV series. (In Daily news–post. [Monrovia, Calif.] Sept. 8, 1961), PS3537.I85 Z892 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair in jail, wheels rock, writes poem, likes both. (From The tribune. Los Angeles. Aug. 3, 1911), PS3537.I85 Z895 (Box No Box)
- An Upton Sinclair "Lark" (From Roycroft magazine. 1918. p. 165–167) Discussion of his "Profits of religion.", PS3537.I85 Z897 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair loses $200,000 libel suit. (In Editor & publisher the Fourth Estate. June 22, 1929. p. 12) A news item., PS3537.I85 Z899 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair okays series on 'Lanny Budd' (In The desert sun. Palm Springs, Calif. Sept. 13, 1961. p. 6A), PS3537.I85 Z8994 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair on "How to End Poverty In California." (In The Plymouth bulletin. Oakland, Calif.: Plymouth Congregational Church. v. 3, no. 41, Dec. 17, 1933) Notice of a speech to be delivered by Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z8996 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair: millions a year. (In The register. Adelaide, Australia. Oct. 27, 1928) A newspaper clipping., PS3537.I85 Z9 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair, prisoner, vanishes. (From Los Angeles Times. v. 42, May 16, 1923. p. [1]) A news item., PS3537.I85 Z92 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair, Socialist candidate for governor, is to open campaign at picnic Sunday. (From The new era. Los Angeles. v. 1, no. 8, Sept. 1930. p. 1), PS3537.I85 Z926 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair talks at harbor. (In Los Angeles Examiner. May 24, 1923), PS3537.I85 Z9261 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair to wed widow. (In Progress–bulletin. Pomona, Calif. Oct. 11, 1961. p. [1]: port.), PS3537.I85 Z92614 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair – will his EPIC plan succeed? (In Your astrology magazine. Oct. 1934. p. 3–4, 40), PS3537.I85 Z9264 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair: wise wanderer in the world of worlds. (In The Kapustkan. Chicago. v. 3, no. 1, Apr. 1942. p. 17) An appreciation and analysis of Sinclair's Between two worlds. Mimeographed., PS3537.I85 Z927 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's books feature court hearings: statements from author's writings are read before jury in trial of libel case. (From Rocky Mountain news. Denver. [1932] p. 1–2), PS3537.I85 Z928 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's chances. (In The new republic. v. 80, no. 1032, Sept. 12, 1934. p. 117) Discussion of Sinclair's chances of being elected governor of California., PS3537.I85 Z9285 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's joke. (From The Argonaut. [1908] p. 323) An editorial condemning Sinclair's "Metropolis.", PS3537.I85 Z929 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's latest. (In The China digest. Nov. 25, 1933. p. 229) Review of Sinclair's "The way out.", PS3537.I85 Z9296 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's wall: Upton Sinclair having cleaned up the Chicago packing houses and precipitated government inspection of meats by his sickening Jungle book, took a little leisure in which to secure a divorce. (In Detroit tribune. Nov. 1, 1913), PS3537.I85 Z93 (Box No Box)
- V.–T., J. Upton Sinclair for the Nobel prize. (In Books and authors. May 1932. p. 288–290) Article signed at end: J.V.–T., PS3537.I85 Z935 (Box No Box)
- Valencia will stage new play. (From the San Francisco call. Jan. 10, 1909. 1 p.) Clipping gives a summary of the play Prince Hagen., PS3537.I85 Z9406 (Box No Box)
- Vallely, Mrs. Jack. Book stuff / by Mrs. Jack Vallely. (In Rob Wagner's script. Beverly Hills, Calif. v. 7, no. 171. p. 20–21: ill.) A review of Sinclair's American outpost., PS3537.I85 Z941 (Box No Box)
- Veterans' Non–Partisan League, Los Angeles. To the veterans of American wars: is Upton Sinclair for Americanism?: or Communism: here's the answer. [Los Angeles, 1930?] [6] p.; 8vo. Includes poem by Sinclair: The red flag., PS3537.I85 Z942102 (Box No Box)
- Waldron, Webb, b. 1882. Can Sinclair win?: the astonishing sweep of the EPIC plan outrages the souls of my citizens, but election day nears with the result in doubt / by Webb Waldron. (In Today. Oct. 6, 1934. p. 6–7, 20, 22: port.), PS3537.I85 Z942104 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Walker, Maud Davis. Sinclair and his band of mourners make Rockefeller's life miserable. (In Appeal to reason. Girard, Kan. no. 963, Apr. 1914. p. 1–2) Feature article on the picketing of John D. Rockefeller's office in New York City on April 29, 1914., PS3537.I85 Z942105 (Box No Box)
- Walker, Ryan, 1870–1932. Tame socialists I have known / by Ryan Walker. (A clipping from an unidentified newspaper) A cartoon., PS3537.I85 Z942107 (Box No Box)
- Walther, Gerda. Upton Sinclair 75 Jahre alt. (In Neue Wissenschaft. v. 4, no. 1, Jan. 1954. p. 34–35) Author's inscribed presentation copy to Upton Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z942109 2 copies (Box No Box)
- "War": a manifesto against it: powerful article by Upton Sinclair. (In The banner daily truth. Broken Hill, Australia. v. 1, no. 252, Aug. 24, 1909. p. 2: port.) A news item concerning the forthcoming appearance of the article by Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z9422 (Box No Box)
- Ware, Harlan. Lanny Budd is back: Upton Sinclair's hero has changed ... / by Harlan Ware. (In Pasadena star–news. Apr. 19, 1953) Review of Sinclair's "The return of Lanny Budd.", PS3537.I85 Z9423 (Box No Box)
- Weir, Hugh, 1884– Upton Sinclair — the man of the hour. (In Human life: the magazine about people. Boston. v. 3, no. 6, Sept. 1906. p. 5–6, 8: ill., port.), PS3537.I85 Z9424 (Box No Box)
- West, Geoffrey, 1900– America's greatest socialist writer / by Geoffrey West. (From The daily herald. London. Aug. 24, 1927. p. 9: port.) Together with "Sinclair's latest and greatest," by Geoffrey West from the August 26, 1927 issue of the Daily Herald. Refers to Sinclairs's latest novel "Oil.", PS3537.I85 Z943 2 copies (Box No Box)
- West, Geoffrey, 1900– Upton Sinclair, the foremost socialist pamphleteer / by Geoffrey West. (From The Millgate monthly. v. 24, no. 285. p. [515]–519: port.), PS3537.I85 Z9432 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866–1946. Mr. Upton Sinclair intervenes. (From The academy. London. Apr. 12, 1913) A letter to the editor, concerning Upton Sinclair. A press clipping., PS3537.I85 Z944 (Box No Box)
- The Wet parade in the movies. (In The Congregationalist and herald of Gospel liberty. v. 117, no. 20, May 19, 1932. p. 632) Includes on p. 640–641 a review of Sinclair's American outpost., PS3537.I85 Z9443 (Box No Box)
- Whitaker, Robert, 1863–1944. Book review [of Upton Sinclair presents William Fox] (In The open forum. v. 10, no. 9, Mar. 4, 1933. p. 3), PS3537.I85 Z9444 (Box No Box)
- Whipple, Leon, b. 1882. Portrait of a seeker. (In The world tomorrow. Sept. 1927. p. 376) Signed at end: Leon Whipple. Review of Floyd Dell's Upton Sinclair: a study in social protest., PS3537.I85 Z9447 (Box No Box)
- Whitaker, Robert, 1863–1944. "The people's choice" in California. (In Unity. Nov. 12, 1934. p. 109–112), PS3537.I85 Z9448 (Box No Box)
- White, Arthur K. (Arthur Kent), 1889– Soul suicide / Arthur K. White, editor. (In The dry legion. Denver, Colo. v. 27, no. 12, Dec. 1961. p. [3]–5: port.), PS3537.I85 Z945 (Box No Box)
- Wilshire, Gaylord, 1861–1927. Upton Sinclair against the one–leg dance. (In Wilshire's magazine. v. 17, no. 8, Aug.–Sept. 1913. p. [1]–2) A "catchy" title for a discussion of Sinclair's socialist principles. Includes a letter from Sinclair dated: Letchworth, England, August 9, defending his principles., PS3537.I85 Z947 (Box No Box)
- Upton Sinclair's indictment of the American press. (From Current opinion. May 1920. p. 669–671) At head of title: Assailing the new minotaur. A review of Sinclair's "The brass check." Article unsigned., PS3537.I85 Z9478 (Box No Box)
- Winton, Janet. What does your handwriting tell? / by Janet Winton (graphologist); famous author analyzed. (From New York evening graphic. Nov. 23, 1928) Includes facsimile of Sinclair's handwriting and his portrait., PS3537.I85 Z949 (Box No Box)
- Women in crepe to picket office of Standard Oil: strike mourners will be stationed at Rockefeller's quarters as protest. (From The New York evening world. Apr. 29, 1914. 1 p.) News item concerning a plan conceived by Sinclair to picket the office of John D. Rockefeller as a protest against the killings in the Colorado mine strikes., PS3537.I85 Z9493 (Box No Box)
- Wood, Clement, 1888–1950. Behold the kept press "The brass check" / [reviewed by Clement Wood] (From The Call magazine. New York. [1919] p. 10: port.), PS3537.I85 Z9498 (Box No Box)
- Wood, Clement, 1888–1950. Upton Sinclair / by Clement Wood. (In The Call magazine. Mar. 30, 1918. Section two, p. [20]: port.), PS3537.I85 Z95 2 copies (Box No Box)
- Woodward, William E., 1874–1950. Upton Sinclair. (In The nation. v. 125, no. 3249, Oct. 12, 1927. p. 392–394) A review of Floyd Dell's Upton Sinclair: a study in social protest., PS3537.I85 Z952 (Box No Box)
- Workers of the world. (In John A. Lee's weekly. Auckland, Australia. v. 3, no. 11, Sept. 16, 1942. p. 3) An editorial., PS3537.I85 Z954 (Box No Box)
- The young author who has startled the world. (From The London daily mail. June 6, 1906) Cartoon–portrait of Upton Sinclair., PS3537.I85 Z97 (Box No Box)